Guide to the Center for International Policy Records, 1960-2016 and undated; 1960-ongoing RL.00205
David M. Rubenstein Rare Book & Manuscript Library
- Robert White Papers, 1971-2014
  - Travel, 1988-2004, 8 folders
    Documents collected by White while traveling on CIP business include speeches delivered, travel documents, notes, reciepts, and literature regarding his trip. Arranged alphabetically by folder title.
    - Compton Foundation Cuba trip, 2002 Feb. 15-21 (Box 20)
    - Congressional Haiti trip, 1993 Sept. 24-26 (Box 20)
    - Haiti, 1992 Feb. 6-9 (Box 20)
    - Haiti, 1992 Nov. 19-20 (Box 21)
    - Kabul, Afghanistan, 1988 Apr. 18-24 (Box 21)
    - LASA International Congress, Atlanta, GA, 1994 Mar. 10-Mar. 12 (Box 21)
    - Tegucigalpa, Honduras, 2004 June 30-July 1 (Box 21)
    - Misc. speaking engagements, 1999-2002 (Box 21)
- Adam Isacson Papers, 1987-2006 and undated
  Contains files house papers of Adam Isacson, a senior associate and program director of the Center for International Policy. Adam Isacson was hired as program director of the Colombia and Demilitarization of Latin America program in 1995. Prior to that he worked previously for the Arias Foundation for Peace and Human Progress in San José, Costa Rica. Mr. Isacson has worked on Latin American security issues, particularly U.S. policy toward Central America and Colombia. He has been to Colombia more than twenty-five times and visited thirteen of the country's thirty-two departments. Adam Isacson's papers are divided into four subseries: Correspondence, Speeches, Subject Files (the largest section), and Travel Files.
  - Correspondence, 1995-2009; 1 folder
    Consists of business-related exchanges between Isacson and various correspondents. There are also digital files of email correspondence. Arranged alphabetically by name.
    - Correspondence, 1995-2005 (Box 23)
    - Correspondence, 2005-2009 (Box 93)
      Personal and professional correspondence related to role at Center for Intenrational Policy.
  - Speeches, 1999-2003 and undated, 5 folders
    Contains speeches in English and Spanish given by Isacson relating to Colombia; includes transparencies used by Isacson for his speeches. They are arranged alphabetically by subject name.
    - Colombia, 2003 Mar. 17-20 (Box 23)
    - Counter narcotics, undated (Box 23)
    - Demilitarization, undated (Box 23)
    - Miscellaneous speeches, 1999 Mar. 23 and undated (Box 23)
    - Transparencies, undated (Box 24)
  - Subject Files, 1987-2013; 20 boxes
    Contains Isacson's research files, comprising the bulk of his papers. The subject files center around individuals, organizations, and countries, and are arranged alphabetically by folder title.
    - Academy for Educational Development, 2000-2001 (Box 24)
    - Acción Ecológica (Ecuador), 2001-2004 (Box 24)
    - Action Center, 2003 (Box 24)
    - Afghanistan, 2004 (Box 24)
    - Alliance for a Responsible, Plural and United World, undated (Box 24)
    - Almario, Luis F., 2006 (Box 93)
    - ALOP- Peru, 2005 (Box 93)
    - Amnesty International, 2002 (Box 24)
    - Andean Commission of Jurists, undated (Box 24)
    - Andersson, Allen, 2003-4 (Box 24)
    - Arias Foundation, 2001-2003 (Box 24)
    - Asylum Cases, 2004 (Box 24)
    - ATWG, 2002 (Box 24)
    - Ayres, Bob, 2002-2003 (Box 24)
    - Baker, Raymond (2 folders), 2003 (Box 24)
    - Ball, Nicole, 2002 (Box 24)
    - Banta, Lucille, 2002 (Box 24)
    - Basic, 1999 (Box 24)
    - Bolivia - Other, 2000-2002 (Box 24)
    - Brookings Institution, 1999-2002 (Box 24)
    - Cabieses, Hugo, 2001 (Box 24)
    - CAF Conference, 2008 Sept. (Box 93)
    - Campamento Internacional (Ecuador), 2002 (Box 24)
    - CEDHU (Ecuador), 2003 (Box 24)
    - CEEN (Nicaragua), 1998-9 (Box 24)
    - Central America (2 folders), 1992-2004 (Box 25)
    - CEPAD (Nicaragua), 2004 (Box 25)
    - CEPAL/ECLAC, 2001-2 (Box 25)
    - Child soldiers, 2003 (Box 25)
    - Center for Hemispheric Defense Studies, 1997-1998 (Box 25)
    - CIP Administrative Documents, 2008-2009 (Box 93)
    - CIP Conference at Brookings, 2002 Mar. (Box 35)
    - CIP Financial Documents, 1990-2009 (Box 93)
    - CIP Human Resources, Undated (Box 93)
    - Colombia, 1987-2007
      - ABC Group, 2001 (Box 25)
      - Acción Andina/TNI, 1999-2001 (Box 25)
      - Actualidad Colombiana, 2000 (Box 25)
      - Adams, David, 1999 (Box 25)
      - Colombia: Adams, David (Box 44)
      - Advocacy Project, 2001-2002 (Box 25)
      - A.E.I., 2002-2004 (Box 25)
      - AFL-CIO, 2000-2006 (Box 25)
      - Colombia: AFL-CIO (Box 44)
      - Afro Colombians, 2004 (Box 25)
      - AFRODES, 2001 (Box 25)
      - AFSC, 2000-2001 (Box 25)
      - Colombia: AFSC (Box 44)
      - Agrupación Familiares de Detenidos Desaparecidos (Box 25)
      - Aid Legislation, 1999-2003 (Box 25)
      - ALOP, 2002 (Box 25)
      - Amnesty International, 1997-2002 (Box 25)
      - ANDAS, 1990-2000 (Box 25)
      - ANIF, 2002 (Box 25)
      - ANUC, 2001 (Box 25)
      - Aruaca, 1993-2002 (Box 26)
      - Army War College, 2001-2002 (Box 26)
      - Asamblea Permanente (2 folders), 1998-2004 (Box 26)
      - Asfamipaz, 2002 (Box 26)
      - ASFADDES, 1999-2000 (Box 26)
      - Asociación Chamanica y Egologica, undated (Box 26)
      - ASPROPAZ (Putumayo), 2002 (Box 26)
      - AUC, undated (Box 26)
      - Banco de Datos (CINEP/JP), 1998 (Box 26)
      - Barrancabermeja, 2001 (Box 26)
      - Barry, Tom, undated (Box 26)
      - Bowden, Mark, 2001 (Box 26)
      - Bring Them Home Campaign, 2003 (Box 26)
      - Cabildo Yura-Yaco, undated (Box 26)
      - Cala, Andres, 1999 (Box 26)
      - Cambio, 2002 (Box 26)
      - Carrigan, Ana, 2000 (Box 26)
      - Casa de la Mujer, 2002 (Box 26)
      - Castaneda, Jorge, 1999 (Box 26)
      - Castrillón, Zilia, 2001 (Box 26)
      - Cauca, 2002 (Box 26)
      - Ceballos, Sandra, 1997 (Box 26)
      - CECORA, undated (Box 26)
      - CEDECOL, 1997 (Box 26)
      - Center for Public Integrity, 2001 (Box 26)
      - Chernick, Marc, undated (Box 26)
      - Chicago Religious Leadership Network, 2000 (Box 26)
      - Christian Peacemaker Teams, 2002 (Box 26)
      - C.I.A., 2004 (Box 26)
      - CIDEC, 2002 (Box 26)
      - CINEP, 1999-2001 (Box 26)
      - CIP (Spain), 2004 (Box 26)
      - Citizen Roundtables, 2001 (Box 26)
      - CNA Corporation, 2000 (Box 26)
      - Coalition Letters/Documents, 2001 (Box 27)
      - CODHES, 1999-2003 (Box 27)
      - Cofan Indigenous Group, 2000 (Box 27)
      - Coffee, 2003 (Box 27)
      - Colectivo de Abogados, 2000-2003 (Box 27)
      - Collier, Robert, 2002 (Box 27)
      - Colnodo, undated (Box 27)
      - Colombia Bulletin, 2000 (Box 27)
      - Colombia HR Network, 1995-2003 (Box 27)
      - Colombia Media Project, undated (Box 27)
      - Colombian Relief Fund, 2002 (Box 27)
      - Colombian Support Network, 1996-2002 (Box 27)
      - Colombian-American Association, 2001 (Box 27)
      - Comisión Colombiana de Juristas, 2003 (Box 27)
      - Comisión de Enlace, 2001 (Box 27)
      - Comité en Solidaridad Presos Políticos, 2001 (Box 27)
      - Compartamos con Colombia, 2003 (Box 27)
      - COMPAZ, undated (Box 27)
      - CPDH-Medellín, 1999 (Box 27)
      - Communist Party, 2000 (Box 27)
      - Conciliation Resources, 2004 (Box 27)
      - Confederación Colombiana de ONG, 1998 (Box 27)
      - Conference Idea, undated (Box 27)
      - Congreso Nacional de Paz y País, 2002 (Box 27)
      - Congress, 2001 (Box 28)
      - Congressional Research Service, 2000 (Box 28)
      - Conservation International, 2000 (Box 28)
      - Contractors, 2003 (Box 28)
      - Contraloría, 2001 (Box 28)
      - Coordinación Col-Eur-USA, 1997-2002 (Box 28)
      - Corpoamazonia, 2000 (Box 28)
      - Corporations, 2000 (Box 28)
      - CFR/IAD Report, 2000 (Box 28)
      - Credhos, 2001 (Box 28)
      - CRIC, 2002 (Box 28)
      - Criminal Justice Policy Foundation, 2000 (Box 28)
      - DEA, 1999-2002 (Box 28)
      - Defense Department, 1997-2001 (Box 28)
      - Defensoría del Pueblo, 2001-2003 (Box 28)
      - Defense Ministry (2 folders), 1997-2004 (Box 28)
      - Destino Colombia, undated (Box 28)
      - Diakonia, 2000 (Box 28)
      - Earthjustice, 2002 (Box 28)
      - Ecofondo, 2003 (Box 28)
      - Economist, 2000-2004 (Box 28)
      - Ecuador Border, 2002 (Box 28)
      - Embassy of Colombia (1 of 4 folders), 2000-2004 (Box 28)
      - Embassy of Colombia (2-4 of 4 folders), 2000-2004 (Box 29)
      - Embrujo Autoritario, 2003 (Box 29)
      - Encuentro Internacional, 2001 (Box 29)
      - ELN, 2002 (Box 29)
      - ESAP, 2000 (Box 29)
      - Escuela Nacional Sindical, 2002 (Box 29)
      - Europe, 2002-2003 (Box 29)
      - Fals Borda, Orlando, 2000 (Box 29)
      - FARC, 2000 (Box 29)
      - FCNL, 2000-2001 (Box 29)
      - FEDEGAN, 1999 (Box 29)
      - FO (France), 2002 (Box 29)
      - Colombia: FO (France) (Box 44)
      - FOCAL (Canada), 2000 (Box 29)
      - F.O.R., 2000-2002 (Box 29)
      - Foreign Aid, 2004 (Box 29)
      - Foro Nacional Por Colombia, 1988 (Box 29)
      - Freidrich Ebert, 2004 (Box 29)
      - Friends of the Earth, undated (Box 29)
      - Fundescopa, 2001 (Box 29)
      - GAO (2 folders), 1998-2002 (Box 29)
      - García-Peña, Daniel, 2004 (Box 29)
      - Garzon, Luis, 2003 (Box 29)
      - George Mason University, 2001 (Box 29)
      - Georgetown University (1 of 2 folders), 2002-2004 (Box 29)
      - Georgetown University (2 of 2 folders), 2002-2004 (Box 30)
      - Global Exchange, 2000 (Box 30)
      - Goff, Stan, 1999 (Box 30)
      - Gold-Bliss, Michael, undated (Box 30)
      - Governors (South), 2000 (Box 30)
      - Gropman, Alan, undated (Box 30)
      - Grupo Civil de Monitoreo (Ecuador), 2001 (Box 30)
      - Grupo de Apoyo a los Desaparecidos, 1999-2000 (Box 30)
      - Guerilla Correspondence, 1999-2000 (Box 30)
      - Harken, 1999-2000 (Box 30)
      - Heritage Foundation, 1999 (Box 30)
      - Hill Drops, 2001-2002 (Box 30)
      - Hoover Institution, 2001 (Box 30)
      - House Democrats, 1999-2004 (Box 30)
      - House Republicans, 1998-2003 (Box 30)
      - Human Rights Conditions, 2000-2002 (Box 30)
      - Human Rights Watch, 1998-2003 (Box 30)
      - ICA, 2000 (Box 30)
      - ICG (2 folders), 2002 (Box 30)
      - INDEPAZ, 2003 (Box 30)
      - Institute for Policy Studies, 2000 (Box 30)
      - Instituto Maria Cano, undated (Box 30)
      - IRC, 2003 (Box 30)
      - Instituto Popular de Capacitación, 2001-2002 (Box 30)
      - Interamerican Human Rights Commission, 1997 (Box 30)
      - Jesuit Refugee Service, 2000 (Box 30)
      - Jones, James, 2003 (Box 30)
      - June 1999 Delegation, 1999 (Box 30)
      - Justicia y Paz, 1997 (Box 30)
      - Juventud por el Guaviare, 2001 (Box 30)
      - Kalmanovitz, Salomon, 1998 (Box 31)
      - Kidnap victims, 2002 (Box 31)
      - LASA, 1998 (Box 31)
      - Latinamerica Press, 2002 (Box 31)
      - Latinamerica Press, 2002 (Box 31)
      - Law 70, 1993 (Box 31)
      - LAWG, 1999-2004 (Box 31)
      - Lawyers' Committee, 2000 (Box 31)
      - Leech, Gary, undated (Box 31)
      - Leyva, Alvaro, 2002 (Box 31)
      - Livingstone, Grace, 1999-2000 (Box 31)
      - Lutheran World Relief, 2003 (Box 31)
      - MAELA, 2001 (Box 31)
      - Maginnis, Thomas, 2001 (Box 31)
      - Mandato Cuidadano, 1998-2001 (Box 31)
      - Marks, Tom, 2001 (Box 31)
      - Maryknoll, 2001 (Box 31)
      - Mesas Ciudadanas, 2001 (Box 31)
      - Millett, Richard, undated (Box 31)
      - MINGA (2 folders), 2001-2002 (Box 31)
      - Movimiento del Sur Occidente, 2000 (Box 31)
      - Mujeres Autoras de Paz, undated (Box 31)
      - Murillo, Luis Gilberto, undated (Box 31)
      - Nariño, 2001-2002 (Box 31)
      - National Council of Churches, 2001 (Box 31)
      - National Defense Unit, 1999-2005 (Box 31)
      - National Security Law, 2001 (Box 31)
      - Naya Massacre, 2001 (Box 31)
      - North-South Center, 2002 (Box 31)
      - Observatorio Sobre el Fenómeno de la Droga, 2001 (Box 31)
      - Occidental Petroleum, 2000-2001 (Box 32)
      - OIDACO, 2001-2003 (Box 32)
      - ONDCP, 1999-2000 (Box 32)
      - OPIAC, 2000 (Box 32)
      - Organización Femenina Popular, 2000-2001 (Box 32)
      - Ospina, J.M., 2001 (Box 32)
      - País Libre, 2002 (Box 32)
      - Para, Jacks, 2003 (Box 32)
      - Pastoral Social, 2000-2001 (Box 32)
      - Paz Colombia, 2000-2001 (Box 32)
      - Peace Brigades (2 folders), 1999-2003 (Box 32)
      - Peace on the Table, 1991-1998 (Box 32)
      - Petro, Gustavo, 2004 (Box 32)
      - Photos, undated (Box 32)
      - Pizzaro, Eduardo, 1998 (Box 32)
      - Plan Colombia, 2002 (Box 32)
      - PLANTE, 2001-2002 (Box 32)
      - Police, 2002 (Box 32)
      - Pratt, Timothy, 2000 (Box 33)
      - Proyecto Paz y Desarrollo en Magdalena Medio, 1999 (Box 33)
      - Public Services International, 2002 (Box 33)
      - Putumayo (2 folders), 2000-2002 (Box 33)
      - Putumayo Dept. Govt., 2001-2002 (Box 33)
      - Rand Corporation, 2001 (Box 33)
      - Red de Solidaridad Social, 2000-2001 (Box 33)
      - Red Nacional de Veedurías Ciudadanas, undated (Box 33)
      - Redepaz, 2000 (Box 33)
      - Required Human Rights Reports, 2000-2001 (Box 33)
      - RGRTPC, undated (Box 33)
      - RFK Memorial, 2000 (Box 33)
      - Robinson, Linda, 2001 (Box 33)
      - Rojas, Jairo, 2001 (Box 33)
      - Rosas, Diego, 1999 (Box 33)
      - Ruta Pacífica, 2002-2004 (Box 33)
      - San Andrés, 2002 (Box 33)
      - Senate Democrats, 2000-2003 (Box 33)
      - Senate Republicans, 1999-2003 (Box 33)
      - September visit, 2003 (Box 33)
      - Shifter, Michael, 2000-2002 (Box 33)
      - SINTRAMINERCOL, 1998-2000 (Box 33)
      - Southcom, 2004 (Box 33)
      - Spagat, Michael, 2003 (Box 33)
      - State/ INL (2 folders), 1998-2003 (Box 33)
      - State/ INL, 1998-2003 (Box 34)
      - Steering Committee, 2001-2004 (Box 34)
      - Stokes, Doug, 2001 (Box 34)
      - Symmes, Patrick, 2000 (Box 34)
      - Tafur, Victor, 1999-2000 (Box 34)
      - Tate, Winifred, 2004 (Box 34)
      - Taussig, Michael, 2003 (Box 34)
      - Testimonies, 2002-2004 (Box 34)
      - Theidon, Kim, 2002 (Box 34)
      - Thoumi, Francisco, 2002 (Box 34)
      - Tickner, Arlene, 1999 (Box 34)
      - Transnational Institute, 2001-2003 (Box 34)
      - Tree, Sanho, 2003 (Box 34)
      - UNHCR (2 folders), 2001-2004 (Box 34)
      - Universidad de la Sabana, 2001 (Box 34)
      - Universidad Javeriana, 2001 (Box 34)
      - Universidad Nacional, 2001 (Box 34)
      - University of Georgia, 2001 (Box 34)
      - USAID, 2001-2004 (Box 34)
      - US-Col. Coordinating Office, 1998-2000 (Box 34)
      - US Committee for Refugees, 1998-2000 (Box 34)
      - Uribe, Alvaro, 2002 (Box 34)
      - Uribe, Alvaro, 2002 (Box 35)
      - USIP, 2004 (Box 35)
      - US/LEAP, 2004 (Box 35)
      - USO, 1987-2002 (Box 35)
      - U'wa Indigenous Group, 1999 (Box 35)
      - Valencia, Leon, undated (Box 35)
      - Vargas, Ricardo, 2003 (Box 35)
      - Viva la Ciudadanía, 1998 (Box 35)
      - Senator Wellstone, 2001 (Box 35)
      - Stokes, Doug, 2002 (Box 35)
      - Wilson, Suzanne, 2001 (Box 35)
      - Witness for Peace, 2002 (Box 35)
      - WOLA, 1997-2002 (Box 35)
      - Woodrow Wilson Center (2 folders), 1996-2004 (Box 35)
      - World Bank, 2001 (Box 35)
      - Women Waging Peace, 2004 (Box 35)
      - World Wildlife Fund, 1998 (Box 35)
      - Yale University, 2004 (Box 35)
    - Counternarcotics documents, 1998 (Box 35)
    - Common Sense for Drug Policy, 2000 (Box 35)
    - Communication and Statements by Congress, Undated (Box 93)
    - Contractors, 2001 (Box 35)
    - Council for a Livable World, 1997-2001 (Box 35)
    - Counter-drug aid, 1998-2000 (Box 36)
    - Cuba, 2004 (Box 36)
    - Curry, Frick, undated (Box 36)
    - DEA, 2003 (Box 36)
    - Department of Defense, 2000-2003 (Box 36)
    - Dialogo por una Neuva Alianza, 2009 (Box 93)
    - Digital files, 1998-2004 (Box 36)
    - Drawdowns, 1997-1999 (Box 36)
    - Earth Council, 2001 (Box 36)
    - Ecuador Humanitarian Emergency, Undated (Box 93)
    - Ecuador- OIPAZ, 2003 (Box 36)
    - Eisendrath, Craig, 2002-2003 (Box 36)
    - El Salvador, 1993-2002 (Box 36)
    - Exercise slides (2 folders), 1996-2005 (Box 36)
    - Falcoff, Mark, 2003-2004 (Box 36)
    - Federation of American Scientists, 1996-2002 (Box 36)
    - FLASCO Guatemala, 2002 (Box 36)
    - Forward Operating Locations, 1999-2002 (Box 36)
    - FMF, 1997 (Box 37)
    - FMT Responsibility Act, 2000 (Box 37)
    - FOCAL (Canada), 2002 (Box 37)
    - FOLs, 2000 (Box 37)
    - FOR, 2002 (Box 37)
    - Foreign Military Training Report- Other, 1999-2002 (Box 37)
    - Foreign Policy In Focus, 2001 (Box 37)
    - Free the Slaves, 2002 (Box 37)
    - Fund for Peace, 2002 (Box 37)
    - Fundación Solon, 1999-2003 (Box 37)
    - Goodman, Mel, 2003 (Box 37)
    - Guatemala, 1993-2004 (Box 37)
      Includes WOLA materials and the Truth and Reconciliation Commission report.
    - Grupo Memoria Historico, 2009 (Box 93)
    - Handwritten Notes, Undated (Box 93)
    - Harrison, Selig, 2003-2004 (Box 37)
    - House Armed Services Committee, 2003 (Box 37)
    - Honduras-Other, 1995-1998 (Box 37)
    - Honduras: Other (Box 44)
    - HCA- Other, 1994-1997 (Box 37)
    - Hurricane Mitch, 1999 (Box 38)
    - ICITAP (Dept. of Justice), 1997 (Box 38)
    - Illicit Drug Trade in the UK, 2007 (Box 93)
    - Interconnect, 2001 (Box 38)
    - IMET, 1997 (Box 38)
    - IMET (Expanded) (2 folders), 1997 (Box 38)
    - Inter-American Air Forces Academy, 1998 (Box 38)
    - Inter-American Forum, 2003 (Box 38)
    - Inter-American Foundation, 2001-2003 (Box 38)
    - International Alert, 2003 (Box 38)
    - International Narcotics and Law Enforcement (State Dept.), 1998-1999 (Box 38)
    - Interns, 2003 (Box 38)
    - Inter-Religious Task Force (Ohio), 2000-2002 (Box 38)
    - Job Seekers, 2003-2004 (Box 38)
    - Johns Hopkins, 2002 (Box 38)
    - Joint Task Force- Bravo (Honduras), 1996 (Box 38)
    - Just the Facts
      - Hill Drops, 2001 (Box 38)
      - Others, 1996-2002 (Box 38)
    - Kerry, John, undated (Box 38)
    - LaPlante, Kenneth, 2001 (Box 38)
    - LAPS- Latin American Terrorism, 2009 (Box 93)
    - LASA, 2001-2004 (Box 38)
    - LAWG, 1999-2004 (Box 38)
    - Leahy Law, 1998-2003 (Box 39)
    - Letelier-Moffitt Award, 2004 (Box 39)
    - Lindesmith Center, 2001 (Box 39)
    - Lindsay-Poland, John, 2001 (Box 39)
    - Lumpe, Lora, 2002 (Box 39)
    - MacArthur Foundation, 2008 (Box 93)
    - Maryknoll, 2001 (Box 39)
    - McGuiness, Ann, undated (Box 39)
    - Mexico, 1996-2002
      - GAO Report, 1998 (Box 39)
      - Military Training, 1997-1998 (Box 39)
      - Other, 1997-2002 (Box 39)
      - WOLA, 1996-1997 (Box 39)
    - Military Training, 2004 (Box 39)
    - MIT Center for International Studies, 2007 (Box 93)
    - Monika's Paper, undated (Box 39)
    - NACLA, undated (Box 39)
    - National Security, 2003 (Box 39)
    - NEPAD, 2001 (Box 39)
    - News Clippings, 2007-2009 (Box 93)
    - Nicaragua- Other, 1995-2004 (Box 39)
    - Notes, undated (Box 39)
    - Office move, 2002 (Box 39)
    - OIPAZ-Ecuador (2 folders), 2001-2002 (Box 39)
    - Operation "Enduring Friendship," 2001-2003 (Box 39)
    - Oxfam, 2003 (Box 39)
    - Paint by Numbers, 2004 (Box 39)
    - Panama, 1995-2000
      - CMA Negotiations, 1997-1998 (Box 39)
      - Panama:CMA Negotiations (Box 44)
      - F.O.R., 1995-1999 (Box 39)
      - Other, 1995-2000 (Box 40)
    - Panama (Box 40)
    - Pan American Health Organization, 2001 (Box 40)
    - Peace Brigades International, 1999-2001 (Box 40)
    - "Perspectivas Sobre Estrategia Maritima" by Paul Taylor, 2009 (Box 93)
    - Peru, 1992-2000
      - Military Assistance, 1999 (Box 40)
      - Other, 1997-1998 (Box 40)
      - WOLA, 1992-2000 (Box 40)
    - PIPER, 2004 (Box 40)
    - Pluto Press, 2004 (Box 40)
    - Poorly Performing States, 2002 (Box 40)
    - PRODH (Mexico), 2001-2004 (Box 40)
    - Programs and Pamphlets, Undated (Box 93)
    - Reich, Otto, 2001 (Box 40)
    - Reports Calendar, 2001 (Box 40)
    - RESDAL, 2002 (Box 40)
    - Research on Cuba, 1998 (Box 93)
    - Resource Center, 2002-2004 (Box 40)
    - Rights Action, 2004 (Box 40)
    - Section 1004 Reports, 1998-2004 (Box 40)
    - Section 2011 Reports, 1998-2000 (Box 40)
    - SERPAJ, undated (Box 40)
    - Shiprider Agreement, 2000-2001 (Box 40)
    - SIPRI, 2002 (Box 40)
    - Smihula, John, 2001 (Box 40)
    - Smith Wayne, undated (Box 40)
    - SOA
      - Annual Reports (2 folders), 1998-2000 (Box 40)
    - SOA (Box 41)
      - Congress, 1993-1999 (Box 41)
      - GAO Reports, 1996 (Box 41)
      - Other, 1997-2003 (Box 41)
      - SOA Watch, 2001-2003 (Box 41)
      - SOA Watch (Box 44)
    - Soldini, Don, undated (Box 41)
    - Southern Command (3 folders), 1996-2004
      - Bases, 1998 (Box 41)
      - Human Rights, 1995-1997 (Box 41)
      - Panama, 1996 (Box 41)
      - Testimonies, 1998-2001 (Box 41)
    - Special Forces-Other, 1998 (Box 41)
    - State Department-10/01 Roundtable, 2001 (Box 41)
    - Students for a Sensible Drug Policy, 2001 (Box 41)
    - Traditional CINC Activities (TCA), 1998 (Box 41)
    - Transnational Institute, 1999-2003 (Box 41)
    - UASB (Ecuador), 2003-2005 (Box 41)
    - UNHCR, 2000-2001 (Box 41)
    - United Bank, 2004 (Box 42)
    - United States Institute of Peace, Undated (Box 93)
    - USAID, 2003 (Box 42)
    - Valderrama, Mariano, 2001 (Box 42)
    - Voice of America, 2001 (Box 42)
    - War College, undated (Box 42)
    - Washington Office on Latin America, 2008 (Box 93)
    - Washington Post, 2002 (Box 42)
    - Website, 2005 (Box 42)
    - Weiss, Cora, 2000 (Box 42)
    - Win Without War, 2003 (Box 42)
    - WOLA drug policy project and guide, 1991-2003 (Box 42)
    - Women Waging Peace, 2004 (Box 42)
    - Woodrow Wilson Center, 2002 (Box 42)
    - Woodrow Wilson Institute, 2008-2009 (Box 93)
    - World Affairs Council, 2001 (Box 42)
    - World Bank, 2001 (Box 42)
    - World Policy Institute, 2000 (Box 42)
    - Zirnite, Peter, 1998 (Box 42)
    - Assorted subject files, 2000s; 84 folders 1 box (Box 93)
      Additional subject files collected by Adam Isaacson during his tenure at CIP. Includes information about CIP programs and initiatives in Central America, particularly Colombia, as well as documentation of partner organizations (WOLA, Open Society Institute, etc.) and CIP internal administrative files regarding finances, Congressional spending and budgets, government agencies, and other activities by the Central America program. Some of the files relate to Isaacson's work on asylum cases for Colombia refugees.
    - Colombia subject files, 2000s; 15 folders (Box 94)
      Isaacson's Colombia subject files on refugees, U.S. congressional hearings, CIP lobbying, and other working groups.
  - Travel, 1998-2005, 18 folders
    Files contain documents collected by Isacson while traveling on CIP business. They include speeches, travel documents, notes, receipts, and literature regarding his trip. Included in this sub-suberies are three notebooks in which Isacson writes in great detail about conversations, meetings, and impressions of his trips to Colombia in 2001 and 2004. Arranged alphabetically by folder title.
    - Bolivia, 2004 May 21-29 (Box 42)
    - Carnegie Seminar, New York, NY, 2002 Oct. 21-22 (Box 42)
    - Chicago, 2001 Aug. (Box 42)
    - CITCA Retreat, Raleigh, NC, 2002 Oct. (Box 42)
    - Colombia, 1998 Jan. (Box 42)
    - Colombia, 2001 Mar. (Box 42)
    - Colombia, 2001 Aug. 16-18 (Box 42)
    - Colombia, 2004 Apr. 17-28 (Box 42)
    - Colombia, 2004 Nov. (Box 42)
    - Colombia Forum, Monterey, CA, 2004 Apr. 14-16 (Box 43)
    - Colombia Support Network, Madison, Wisc., 2003 Apr. 3-5 (Box 43)
    - Columbus, Ga., 2002 Nov. 14-16 (Box 43)
    - Columbus, Ohio, 2003 Apr. 17-18 (Box 43)
    - Cornell University, Ithaca, NY, 2005 Nov. 18-19 (Box 43)